let us bring them on the show everybody
they we we're going to talk mainly about
pan quake and the importance of pan
quake and
uh we wanted to bring
both of these gentlemen back on the show
they've both been on the show before um
first of all uh xcia and whistleblower
john cariako was here who uh let's bring
him on the show john how are you hey
doing well thanks graham sorry to hear
about youtube man not good
well dude
that's everybody i know
this is happening to everybody i know
it's awful sorry
i know it's great i mean it's it's
it's it's insane i mean it's happened on
youtube i mean
i i have several friends and i'm sure
you'd know people too worked at rt
america so they just basically wiped rt
america off the face of the earth i mean
like just like that
it's and all these really good shows
rejected tonight on contact boom bust
max kaiser all these shows that i
watched um that
brought news and information to people
in a way that the american media isn't
it's just it's
awful
it's terrible
we live we live in we live in a crazy
we live in crazy times um
but uh we'll bring also on uh
the cso of pan quake who's been on the
show before mr sean o'brien shawn how
you doing
great happy to be here
excellent
well um
let's get right into it uh
about
first of all where pan quake is it's
just i mean it's close to being done
i've talked to susie about it uh
and then i want to really get into the
importance of it
especially
to what we were just talking about john
and i were just talking about and all
the censorship all of us have seen
um
so
why don't sean why don't you just give
us sort of an update of where it's at
and the status of it and then we'll get
into the the reasons why
sure so um as a lot of your audience
knows pancreatic.com is a short
messaging service um we've been um
working on it uh from a development
standpoint since approximately last
summer um
and stuff is moving very very quickly
the development process is going really
fast
we just revealed to the world um the
look and feel so the uh beautiful
screens um showing what a pancake
dashboard will look like um this
environment that we want folks to
be happy living in
um expressing themselves sharing
information you know um and having a
network where they really can feel and
know actually transparently that they're
reaching the folks that they intend to
reach they have the amplification they
should have that they have the voice
that they should have
on social media um so we have uh you
know a functioning uh interface uh john
has seen it
and we have demoed it to some other
folks as well um we're constantly uh
building and adding to that um and we're
push push pushing so we're in the last
phase of our crowd fundraiser so we're a
crowdfunding model here um we've had you
know approximately 3 500 folks donate to
that crowdfunder which is just
incredible um and we need to get through
this last phase get across the goal line
um so we can bring the folks we need to
bring in for things like support um
making sure we have real humans and not
algorithms right
um who are going to help our folks um
you know if they if they need that that
support uh in the network um and just
upping the business really yeah and just
for people look here i've just put this
is what the interface looks like i've
seen it as well it's pretty amazing uh
to see how functional it is and then
to just go back to uh this is how many
people have donated thus far this is the
campaign
uh and
this is
to me already showing
how hungry everybody is for this and and
what it's going to do and it was really
sort of exciting
um
[Music]
for me and for myself for all of us to
to see this one of the things that i
find exciting about it is
that um
you know as a stand-up comedian just to
somebody that that promotes shows i've
been so
um
you know throttled that that i you know
i've amassed followers on all these
social media platforms and then i tell
them
hey i'm coming to your town to perform
or watch my live stream or whatever and
they're like never heard of it they're
not even allowed to hear of it so it's
really just just as a performer not to
mention
uh all the other reasons for to use it
for censorship but um
i want to
like
so john
what what drew you to this project and
how do you see it yeah um
how do you see it interacting with the
intelligence community which which
really has hijacked so many of these
social media platforms
really great
questions this is the best way to open
this conversation what what drew me was
several different things actually
number one i've gotten to the point
where i have to go to my twitter every
day to see if they've put a little red
tag saying that i'm a
an official mouthpiece of the russian
government which i'm not but
i mean poor ed schultz has been dead for
how many years and they made him a
they put a tag on him saying that he's a
mouthpiece of the russian government so
that was one thing that bothers me very
much more importantly though
you know i i used to go to twitter
constantly
to read the news
what what i would do is
because i can't read everything as much
as i would like to
i would follow people that i respect
from a wide variety of backgrounds and
look all day long to see what they're
posting what's ralph nader saying right
what's uh uh the the marshall uh uh
center saying or the brennan center
or propublica
and now it's
you know so much of what i used to be
interested in is banned
or it's you can't see you can't find
telesur you can't find rt or sputnik uh
any anything that i'm interested in that
has to do with prison reform for example
uh is deemed to be anti-american
and so all of a sudden i just can't read
the news anymore facebook's even worse
facebook beat twitter to the punch
they're even worse
and then about a year ago susie dawson
approached me and told me about pan
quake and the idea behind pan quake was
no corporate money no government money
no advertising completely open source
code so that everything is transparent
and i mean like in the literal sense of
the word it's transparent there is
there is no
big brother to
go through
our our uh
posts and then
impose an algorithm on us that's going
to decide what our friends and followers
can see and what they can't see
so
you know we we give a lot of
we give a lot of lip service grab to to
freedom of speech
and to transparency and
nine times out of ten at least here in
the united states with these corporate
run sites we're just not serious about
it
well what
told me that that pancake was serious
about it was the fact that it's hosted
in iceland which i absolutely love
so it's not subject to a national
security letter from the fbi
demanding all of your user data and all
this other nonsense that we see all the
time
in the news
and because there are no
outside investors no corporations or
governments or think tanks or anything
else
there's no pressure to squelch free
speech
so this in my view is what these big
tech
platforms
originally thought they wanted to be
and then realized that they could never
be
never
yeah and they've i mean you especially
you read a book like uh you know when
when google met wikileaks you know you
realize that like google has been
basically doing data collection for the
intelligence community for quite a while
so absolutely absolutely you know i
remember oh it's been 10 or 12 years now
when uh somebody i don't know who
somebody leaked to wikileaks that it
wasn't just google it was literally
every one of the big tech firms from
from microsoft to google to apple to all
the big communications companies every
last one of them
was providing information to the cia
into nsa and to the fbi with these
national security letters well you have
to ask yourself when the director of
security
for microsoft
is the former station chief well i
shouldn't say where he was the station
chief but
you know there's a problem there's a
problem with this how do we trust this
company
well
i can trust
yeah and that's the thing that's so
fascinating to me is like in in you know
in and how susie's explained it to me
and to all of us like i'm you know i'm
not a coder i'm not a tech guy at all
and so
the questions that have come up like
um
and because susie's been targeted
herself and because she
knew julian and and understands how this
works
they put in you guys have put in so much
stuff to
prevent all of this like the iceland
thing i never even would have thought of
that you know like and the the the
servers are not amazon servers because
that's boom they can they can just call
up amazon say shut it down and it's done
and
jeff bezos has got 600 million dollars
from the cia so we
you know we know where where was that
so
um
i want to like uh some of the questions
and sean i know you can you can answer
these
um
the questions of like
can it be
hacked can it be can can somebody just
come in and buy pan quake and snatch up
all your data it is always all the data
going to be stored somewhere so everyone
can steal it or hack it or whatever can
you answer those questions for anybody
sure um and first i just want to say you
know the points you're making and the
the way we're talking about this is
absolutely correct right um we want to
be a lifeboat away from big tech and
that's you know an analogy of course but
it's a one we really really mean um
protecting data is actually protecting
lives um you know especially when we're
talking about you know high value
targets for the cia et cetera et cetera
um activists um who are making an impact
right there they know that they're being
targeted it has a real effect on their
lives and these other social media sites
that are advertising surveilling you
know creating these frameworks which
were in turn work with these state
agencies
they are exposing people to real harm
and real danger so um that's exactly the
thing that we care about um you know
protecting people from
and uh that's why we're building things
the way we're building them so
on the building piece um
so yeah we have our core infrastructure
in iceland um it's a good jurisdiction
for you know freedom of speech and a
number of other protections from
specifically the us government but other
governments as well
but also we have a decentralized model
right we have a blockchain based model
and our
nodes the machines the people right with
smartphones and desktop computers and so
on that will be in pancake.com those
folks will be communicating to each
other using peer-to-peer connections
right so we're making sure we're using
the edge of the network we're having
folks
communicate in a decentralized not cloud
computing way
and that
in turn makes a network very resilient
against things like you know ddosing and
other kinds of attacks that could bring
it down right um we spread out the
computing as far as we possibly can um
we make sure we have strong encryption
strong um you know authentication and
verification of users between other
users and we have some clever encryption
where we're uh implementing to do all of
that
um we make sure that uh we have open
source code right so we're gonna release
uh
with the pan quake launch we're gonna
release the code for the entire stack um
that means anybody can review and audit
that and we will have the best and
brightest security experts and already
do have quite a few um looking at that
work looking at that code um so that's
our sort of the fundamental things but
if you care about protecting data right
don't take that data in in the first
place okay one of the analogies that a
lot of security experts talk about is
data as what they call a toxic asset
and that means basically you know the
more data you collect the more you sort
of put it on a shelf somewhere it's like
a corroding battery that just gets worse
and worse and worse these other services
right that we're so used to using on the
internet have these huge databases these
huge server farms that have all this
information on their users all these
profiles and so on um at pan quake right
we don't want that data in the first
place okay
anything that's even remotely sensitive
will be on your machine so we're
architecting it so that you have a user
data store on your devices um and that's
your data you own it we don't want it um
you're not even collecting the data
right that's right that's exactly right
so
you don't even
it's incredible right yeah it's
incredible i love it yeah but it's so
simple really and and you know we're not
going to collect email addresses or
phone numbers or those kinds of things
that folks are now having to use all the
time to verify themselves on these other
networks we don't want it right um
that's good for us right and it's good
for you um and that's that's the basic
principle there um the nuts and bolts of
how it works i mean we're taking some
very clever pieces of software some very
clever encryption um we're
decentralizing and spreading things out
like true peer-to-peer networks um we're
doing a lot of the things which you know
other transformative you know um apps
are doing um to change the the world and
this thing that some folks are starting
to call web three right although we'll
see if that catches on um but the point
is you know it's about breaking down
these control structures breaking down
the centralization of the network
environment that we have which is what
allows the googles etc etc to have the
censorship that they have but it also
allows them right to basically ruin
people's lives by amassing these huge
profiles on people and then following
them throughout their entire childhood
now i mean the people who've grown up in
this environment all the way through you
know they hope that you know the end of
their lives that's that's the google
plan right um and that's something we
not only would never do we don't want to
do it um and because we're not focusing
on spying on people right like these
other companies are and they put all
this engineering effort into trying to
figure out who people are and who
they're talking to and how to stop them
from talking to specific people or stop
them from sharing different information
that takes a lot of engineering work
right um because we're not doing all
that we can use our engineering muscle
right to deliver something different
that allows information to be amplified
freely allows you to reach your audience
and know verifiably and transparently
with the blockchain record that you're
reaching your audience and so on and so
forth um it's
it's simple right it's it's in some ways
going back to you know the better part
of the internet before it was destroyed
in the last you know 10 15 20 years by
these big tech companies and we're using
the lessons and the cool technology
that's out now to reinvent that internet
into something that's better and more
powerful so
well that's
yeah that's got to have them all
befuddled because you're not creating
something to try to take over the world
and become billionaires and build rocket
ships to fly away from a planet that you
let set on fire um so i wanted to
and since we've all said we've all seen
you know how they've used infiltrated
social media like the intelligence and
stuff to to blow up activist movements
there's you see these infiltrators you
know they'll have a pro a profile that
you know
you look to read the purple boy they
seem like they're a real true lefty
activist it says free assange and
medicare for all or whatever else and
then they're always like stirring [__]
up or whatever
um
so i wanted to
sean
quickly tell us
like how that works in terms of the
the giving someone a pan quake and
giving them the authority to do that so
that even because because the question
is like okay so you guys are doing five
dollars a month subscription what's to
prevent google or the cia or whomever to
buy a bunch of bot accounts and then
they can just take this thing over and
in six months to a year it'll be ruined
again just like the last cool thing we
thought was gonna be great that's not
ruined
sure sure um so there's a few mechanisms
that we're sort of building in at a
fundamental level we'll obviously also
have checks and balances uh you know um
intrusion detection systems and so on so
that we can start spotting you know real
attacks on the network but putting aside
that technical stuff um first off the
subscriber model is a good way to limit
um things like botnets like all these
bots um you know swarming and creating
these you know what used to be called
egg accounts on twitter right these
these bs accounts with 30 followers that
just harass people and and make people's
lives miserable um that subscription
actually does help to limit that
somewhat um you know the types of tools
that you know the cia the nsa uses to
spin up these fake personas as they call
them in their own documents um
that is not going to be easy to do um
when you have a subscription model so
that's that's sort of the first thing
right because i guess really if they
want to buy a bunch of bots well that's
thanks for the five bucks from all these
robots
that's one way to think about it do they
really want to be funding us right
so
at any rate um
the second part is that um it's an
opt-in
social network in the sense that you're
going to see content from the people you
follow or content for example that you
might search for so if you search for
cats you're going to see cats right um
that's not a very effective network for
spies to use to amplify content and
manipulate people right
because what they rely upon is spinning
up these you know groups of fake
accounts so that they can basically push
their narrative so that they can have
you know these fake trolling
conversations shove things into people's
timelines manipulate um on the back end
when they can the algorithm to silence
some voices and to allow some other
voices to be bigger so that their voices
the bots that they control the paid
staff that they pay to manipulate social
feeds those folks suddenly have a huge
voice in these big tech networks right
none of that's going to be possible in
pan quake
folks have a level playing field which
is very big to us and it's not just
about you know the spies and all of that
which certainly is a problem that we're
well well aware of um but we want to be
somebody who's you know just um starting
out uh trying to promote content such as
yourself graham i mean you're not just
starting out but you would be when you
get into pancake new there um we want
you to have equal footing to you know
if i don't know somebody who was uh some
huge star came into the network right
we want to know that those accounts
start out on equal footing have the
ability to amplify have the ability to
reach their followers and folks will
find that they have a voice that where
they don't feel like they're you know in
some sort of popularity contest right
a lot of that again is just about not
manipulating timelines right not
manipulating content not forcing fake
trends into people's faces that are
advertising the next disney thing
um we're not doing any of that but that
that also makes it so that a lot of the
abuse a lot of the things that facebook
especially has been called out for um
can't happen in the network um if you're
not manipulating algorithms you know to
do this terrible stuff to do you know
manipulation of uh political beliefs for
you know some sort of political campaign
and so on and so forth um
then you know uh
there's there's a lot less to worry
about as far as folks who are worried
about you know these kinds of uh um i
don't know these social uh uh
engineers let's say
uh
if we get us you know uh someone in
there who is trying to manipulate people
they're going to find it's going to be
very very difficult with the way that
we're just having opt-in content no
trend manipulation no timeline
manipulation and honest transparency
about statistics um that alone is going
to make it really hard for these folks
to operate the way that they're used to
operating in the big tech environment
yeah and so let me ask you this john so
like you've obviously experienced first
hand the targeting for being a
whistleblower you've seen it
you know the assange movement the
wikileaks has been targeted i mean susie
dawson just put in the chat how
they shut down the paypal donations
during the fundraising of this
and so how do you
what i mean like we have to think in
these terms and this is the thing i
liked in the conversations i had with
susie is she's assuming these attacks
are going to come she's not like let's
hope they play nice we know they're not
going to play nice we know what they're
going to do so what attack what things
do you see
them trying to do to shut down pan quake
john and how do you see pan quake being
able to with withstand these attacks
um yeah you know i'm confident that
susie and sean and the team have
foreseen
a lot of what
we ought to be expecting basing basing
the the servers in iceland i think was a
stroke of genius even the corporate
headquarters is um is offshore in a in a
place that's very
secure for this kind of thing
very very forward thinking um
if i were still at the cia or nsa i
would be looking for a technical way in
i think that the fact that
there's this subscription service which
makes it almost impossible to create
bots to attack the system unless the
bots pay
you know the five dollars a month
was also uh brilliant uh what the cia
well i would expect different things
from the cia from nsa nsa i would expect
technical attacks and bill benny bill
binney's on the team bill can go into
some deep detail on that kind of thing
he's he's a genius
on the cia side
i would expect um
a different kind of underhandedness i
would expect uh personal attacks on pan
quake's leadership i would i would
expect um
uh
articles uh condemning
all of us who are involved for whatever
reason oh john kiriakou he's a convicted
felon
you want to be in business with a
convicted felon you know i get that all
the time from people who can't debate on
the issues
so uh you know what they did to to
wikileaks
uh allowed us to learn
lessons and we've been able to safeguard
ourselves to protect ourselves from
those kinds of attacks it's going to be
much much harder to attack pan quake
than it is to attack wikileaks and
because pan quake is still so small it's
still you know in its nascent stages
i think we largely haven't come to their
attention yet
and i'm i'm optimistic that once we do
come to their attention once we're big
enough or important enough to be worth
attacking
will be
so ready for them that there won't be
anything that they can do
well yeah i mean it will get i can't
wait for the article that pat quake is
helping putin or whatever whatever
you know it's coming
you know
they're going to hashtag putin quake or
whatever right right
quake great yeah just like just like ed
snowden defected to russia like nobody
in america remembers that he was in the
transit lounge when john kerry revoked
his passport so yeah histories change as
time passes it's going to be up to us to
make sure that the truth is out there
which again pancake will afford us that
safe place to do it and i want people to
understand that
this wasn't just like something slapped
together you've got bill benny involved
nsa whistleblower john you're a cia
whistleblower involved you've got susie
who's been targeted you've got people
who played this game
and see the tactics and so
you know let's all just be ready for the
whatever pan quake kills puppies
headline from cnn or whatever whatever
whatever exactly that's how you know
you're making an impact right yeah how
else are you gonna attack the former
number four at nsa nsa's technical
director who's arguably one of the
the greatest minds in america on the
issue of internet security and privacy
how else are you going to attack him
right yeah you've got to say he he he
killed christmas or whatever
bill benny hates rainbows or whatever
they're going to whatever they're going
to say um
so um and i the thing too i want i want
to
talk about this as well because susie
one of the things our conversation her
and i had was about
she wants to be ready
to have staff in place so that if it
takes off it's not overwhelmed because
that's another thing too we get all of a
sudden you know two million people sign
up for this thing in in 20 days oh we
don't we don't know we don't have the
staff in place to do that so what what
steps are you guys taking in case that
which is a which would be a good problem
to have
um for that to be handled
so we have a staggered release model
right um so first i just want to say you
know if you folks are interested in our
progress and how we're building in the
direction we're moving in and why we're
making certain choices and so on we do
monthly delivery meetings um where we
recap basically everything that happened
in the month both the technical stuff
and the non-technical um and we just
make sure we have that transparency for
all of our donors and the public in
general um but yeah uh we do staggered
releases basically so uh first off uh we
are having a beta right and that beta
will have five thousand users in it if
folks would like to apply to potentially
be someone who can join the beta um you
can go out to pancreatic.com there's a
link to apply to join the beta we just
want to make sure we do a little bit of
vetting and and
we don't have bots warming us at the
beginning
all right so that's the kind of thing
we're being smart about and and that
that model is very smart um that way um
and not just bots but you know
disruptive folks and so on we want to
have we like disrupted folks of a
certain kind but we
we want to have trustworthy folks in the
network who really care about what we're
doing and and uh and so on and so forth
that's a smart thing to do
and then we go to the 1.1
and we're going to get to 25 000 users
for that release um so we're just having
just a little bit larger for that and
then we will open it to the public and
have sort of this staggered release
model that allows us to make sure
especially with a blockchain right we
have to have that core of trust in the
beginning um the folks who are part of
what's called a consensus model and and
uh your audience who are cryptocurrency
folks i'm sure familiar with this kind
of thing um you need to make sure that
that core is uh non-malicious actors
basically um so we have to have that
really trusted core of folks in the
beginning um and then we just sort of
move out and branch out the um support
plan which is something that the staff
is working on um in which i'm sure we
will uh
talk about this month in the delivery
meeting and probably continue to talk
about um is very smart um we're making
sure that we're scaling and planning to
scale you know having real humans who
can help real people and um doing that
and making sure that's in place giving
people that different experience from
you know all this algorithmic you know
bs that they're used to um is also
really important to us right we want
people to be respected we're building
respect in
not just into the technology right but
also into the way that we're building
the infrastructure around that the human
infrastructure around that um so that's
that's really a big part of it but also
i will say like this decentralization
stuff right um which has already changed
the world with you know cryptocurrency
and and some other decentralized apps
that are out there d apps or whatever
folks want to call it um it's really
powerful it's really scalable
so we can plan sort of a staging of
bringing more and more nodes online
expanding the network out across
continents and so on and so forth um
we're using the pipe in very efficient
ways so to speak right we're not just
funneling a bunch of data into a google
data center somewhere or relying upon
some amazon aws server that we're
renting you know that's not even ours
and um that kind of thing allows us to
really plan in a smart way um
we don't want to be like some of these
networks that folks may be familiar with
the the getters which had you know
getter had all kinds of problems to put
it mildly um true social the trump
network that
seems to have fallen apart before it
started barely um
that kind of thing are the mistakes that
we know well are well aware of and we
can make sure that we don't do
um but also i mean look we want to have
uh
something sustainable here um we're not
trying to as as we said you know have uh
vc money or corporate pr teams we don't
have corporate marketing teams
everything we've raised to this point is
graph grassroots money um from folks who
are donating their hard-earned cash to
us to do something amazing um and that's
been done you know with word of mouth
our word of mouth and speaking to each
other human to human is really really
powerful um so we have regular people
being our voice we're going to get that
critical mass and when we get there
right we get those folks on board and we
can't be ignored by the corporations and
these other folks you know that's when
you'll see the smear pieces certainly
but that's also when you're going to see
a situation where we can't be ignored
and we're on the front pages right um
you have to build it that way and that's
a lesson really that you know we learned
in in some respect from from wikileaks
right um
they built something that couldn't be
ignored there um they were releasing
information that was vitally you know
important um and did it in such a clever
way especially with i mean with the
numerous releases that they did um
that you know even though the mainstream
media didn't want to report this stuff
they had to right and um that's sort of
the thing that we're learning and trying
to do with pan quake as well we want to
be something big
that people care about that people are
part of real ordinary folks and then you
know um
conquer the world let's hope we'll see
uh so real quick folks if you're
watching and you want to ask any direct
questions go to rockfin.com grandma if
you do the tip i will answer those
questions so um john
as we're you know it's great hearing
this
tiered um release
um or staggered releases it was called
and knowing again was as you just
brought up what the tactics you know
does nsa and the cia with the text would
be you know when pancake becomes
this bigger thing that
they'll take notice of once it's a
threat that they can't they can't
disrupt it in the traditional ways
how do you see this potentially changing
just the landscape of freedom of speech
because we're in a country now that is
not a democracy if you're shutting down
rt right
it's not a democracy i mean that's that
was so then they should be able to if
you don't like what they're saying well
then are we going to shut down fox news
next i don't like i don't i don't agree
with fox news i don't agree with msnbc
do we shut them down i mean
so uh because you know like i said i've
been i've been demonetized for 15 months
now and yeah
i'm a comedian in my in an apartment you
know what i mean talking about uh
you know what's wrong with this country
and how and i'm a threat i'm a threat
i'm a comedian who who talks about
surfing and batman is also a threat like
this is just maddening to me so how do
you see yeah
this is why the prosecution of julian
assange is so dangerous that that this
exactly is the reason why
julian's
case is such a slippery slope
because you use the uh the espionage act
to prosecute a journalist and even if
you don't believe that he's a journalist
which i do
you can't deny that he's a publisher
and so
if he's convicted under the espionage
act
then what's to keep the washington post
national security reporter from being
convicted or the wall street journal the
new york times
whoever in the white house happens to be
in the white house if he doesn't like
something that's been written and
there's one little kernel of
information that you know
may or may not be legitimately
classified what's to keep the white
house from going after that next person
so we're we're all in danger you're
you're exactly right graham that we're
not in a democracy
if we were in a democracy we as adults
would be able to choose
the sources
of news that we want to consume
and we just simply can't do that
i can't go anymore to press tv
to get the iranian side of a story or to
telesur or to rt america i can't even go
to al jazeera america it doesn't even
exist anymore
so this is something that is going to
i think open a
a path
that
had been closed or has been closed uh to
us
this is this is
mccarthyism
all over again i i hate speaking in
hyperbole but i really don't believe
this is hyperbole it's dangerous
you know this is another thing and
forgive me for getting on a soapbox but
when i was um when i was assigned to the
state department for a few years i was
the human rights officer and i had to i
had to write the human rights report
every year for the country that i was
assigned to i was in bahrain and uh and
sent to congress and i used to say you
know we we profess to be this shining
beacon of hope
for democracy and civil rights and human
rights and civil liberties and it's
[__]
you know what what would a host country
think for example
when
john kiriakou the human rights guy goes
into the minister of interior's office
and says your excellency i have to warn
you
your
your men beat this 15 year old boy to
death the other day because he marched
in a pro-democracy demonstration that is
illegal it's an extra
judicial killing and i'm going to put it
in the human rights report
and then 15 minutes later the cia
station chief walks in and says
don't listen to the human rights guy
we want you to open a secret prison here
where we can bring people to be tortured
don't tell anybody and we're going to
give you 50 million dollars to cover the
costs and grease the right palms
well it's the same thing with
information
we say one thing and then we do the
completely opposite thing
this is an antidote to that
it's an antidote because it's based
overseas it is utterly and completely
transparent
and will pro will protect the system
the system will protect itself
so people really can
have a free exchange of ideas something
that just simply doesn't exist on
twitter on facebook on youtube or on any
of these other uh platforms not anymore
and something i just want to make sure i
add there too you know we talk about the
espionage act right and how atrocious it
is that's being used in this way look um
julian's not an american citizen right
it's unreal right so it just goes to
show the danger of you know real power
in these situations um
we at pan quake we not only understand
these kinds of things but we take our
role seriously as an international
presence right we're not going to be
doing the bidding of some government
based upon some government thing right
we really want to have an information
system that has free flow of information
all over the world between anybody who
wants to connect to anybody else using
our network and that's the thing that
really um is sacrosanct about the model
we're trying to build
you know so i i founded something called
privacy lab at yale that's part of
something called the information society
project it's called that because we have
an information society right um and we
need to take seriously the role of free
flow of information and how vital that
is to a democracy if we're going to have
a democracy but also if we're just going
to have normal conversations between you
know as friends as family
without this intense polarization and
animosity that's been brewing
all of that manipulation
all of that that's happened has a lot to
do with the locking down of the
information system some of that is for
private data brokers who want to spy on
us and ostensibly sell us things right
some of that is from these you know uh
government spies and agencies which are
working in tandem with the private you
know um entities and some of that are
folks who are very powerful who are
trying to push propaganda push control
of populations shut down movements shut
down activists shut down anybody who has
an impact that goes against their you
know plans and schemes and um you know
the role that something like
pancreatic.com can play in opening up
that information system can't be
you know uh
overstated um it is absolutely
incredible what can happen when we are
allowed to speak to each other when we
are allowed to make our own decisions
based upon varying information instead
of being sold some lines and propaganda
so
how much do you think
as we wrap up here because i know you
guys got to go i know you've been doing
interviews all day and i appreciate your
time um
how much is the the like the bitcoin
white paper did it influence the uh
formulation of pan quake
that's a general question sure so um
i i love that you say we don't have that
much time left and then give me the no
and then give me this this massive like
there's no way to answer this question
in less than 10 minutes but
it's fine we're not pressed for time i'm
just respecting i know you guys are busy
but those are all you want to answer
so what blockchain technology represents
is a really clever way right of
verifying information reaching consensus
so that you can have machines talk to
each other without central authority
right um so in the sense where bitcoin
does accomplish that although a lot of
it of course has been centralized in
exchanges and so on and so forth
but in the sense where it does
accomplish that that's similar to what
we're trying to do
with pan quake now we care about free
flow of information and content and so
on so we have a content based blockchain
right
but we can have nodes in the network
reach consensus and verify that hey you
know john sent a quake quake is what
we're calling our short messages um and
be able to say hey this belongs on the
blockchain john's a verified you know
pan user and then commit that to the
blockchain record
that blockchain is basically a ledger or
spreadsheet however you want to think of
it
that can then be shared and broadcast
around the world to all these other
machines on the network
unlike the model where you know you have
a big tech company that has some
database somewhere in some unknown
location and they can just tweak and
modify and change it
literally rewriting history right which
we see or ban somebody and just
everything goes poof right um unless
it's been archived and so on and so
forth
but something else i should bring up i
guess just real quickly we take very
seriously um you know the archiving of
information as well um we want to solve
in some way the thing that's called bit
rot right we want to make sure that
people can not only share information
but that the information that they're
sharing on pan quake will be resilient
to censorship itself and we have some
clever things we're working on from that
standpoint too um we want to make sure
if you share an article from something
like al jazeera english or or some other
thing that's being blocked banned or
disappears that there's some permanence
of the information you're sharing in our
network too um so we're working on that
all right
well i mean this is uh i really
appreciate your time and where can
people go to support this
uh pancreatic.com donate um you also can
go pancreatic.com crypto to donate
cryptocurrency um we also have a sub
stack uh talk liberation um which is not
paywall but if you do subscribe your
money for subscribing five dollars a
month um goes towards uh the pancake
build all of that money um those are the
ways you can support us but the other
thing is we need you as regular people
to be our media so far that's how we
succeeded and if you can help amplify us
talk about us um share some of our
videos um share this stream please you
know um that's the way that we're gonna
win that's the way that we're gonna get
there so
amen right on thank you for thank you
especially you know
for doing this taking the time and
especially in light of what just
happened with the julian ruling it's
it's like like john said it's important
now more than ever so
um i appreciate it thank you so much
john kerry
thanks a lot
have a great day you too
hey everybody thanks for watching we are
still in our like ninth month of
demonetization from youtube so support
what we're doing at patreon.com
gramelwood or rockfin.com graham ellwood
which is a blockchain cryptocurrency
platform
it's free to sign up and there's a
premium level at ten dollars a month and
for that you get everybody on the
platform's premium content myself lee
camp ron placone jimmy door whitney webb
kim iverson abby martin and many many
others you can also support what we're
doing at venmo at graham-elwood and go
to gramelwood.com we have a paypal
button and a po box i also have crypto
wallets which are all in the show notes
thanks for supporting what we do
you